Tolga Cömert



Contact information
J. Kinkerstraat 10
3532XT, Utrecht
The Netherlands
+31687142791
comert_tolga@live.nl

PERSONAL OBJECTIVE

My purpose in life is to share knowledge with the whole wide world. By helping people, I want to stimulate humanitarianism and care for each other, ultimately leaving behind a world filled with joy.

CAREER OBJECTIVE

My career should allow me to continuously develop my personal, analytical and communicative skills. In the upcoming years, I want to gain insights into the technical details, while the main focus should, gradually throughout my career, shift to managing large-scale projects. In twenty years, I strive and expect myself to be an executive manager at a leading organisation in the tech industry.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Fugro International Management Trainee

October 2019 – now

- The International Management Traineeship at Fugro has a duration of two years. These two years are divided in three periods of eight months, of which two periods will be spent abroad (i.e. outside the Netherlands). The goal is to gain relevant and extensive knowledge of Fugro's core business, train management and consultant skills and learn more about Fugro as a company at a worldwide scale. At the end of the traineeship, I will start a management role within the organisation.
- The main theme of my traineeship is to further develop Fugro's digitalization by supporting and developing the Digital Foundation of Fugro. The Digital Foundation is a digitised, spatial and Geodata framework; a four dimensional model that provides our clients with a deep understanding of their site and their assets.

Consultant October 2019 – now

The first assignment in my International Management Traineeship at Fugro is at the Water Consultancy
department, located in Utrecht. The Water Consultancy department is mainly operating in Water
Defence and Flood Control projects within the Netherlands. By flood risk assessment and stability of
hydraulic structures, Fugro provides support by mapping the flood risk for entire river and flood plain
systems.

My objectives are to:

- gain in-depth knowledge of the core business of the Water Consultancy department,
- operate as a consultant and train relevant skills,
- support innovation, such as automation.
- In my role, I mainly operate as a consultant. However, next to advising our clients, I also operate as a Hydraulic and Software Engineer. In my technical role, I learn and apply knowledge relevant to the field of Hydraulic Engineering in projects. Furthermore, I develop software and tools to support new ways of running models or easying the process of making calculations. I have built an API with the use of Python which now allows the Water Consultants to make significantly more calculations in much less time, leading to time efficiency increases up to 90%.

Tauw

July 2018 - September 2019

Project Engineer Data Management

• At Tauw, I have designed and programmed new Python tools to improve the efficiency of certain work flows related to the fields of Hydrology and Hydraulic Structures. Furthermore, I have improved modelling standards and promoted the use of automation in multiple projects.

Delft University of Technology

Student Assistant

October 2015 - December 2018

- Helped and tutored students who were participating in Fluid Mechanics (2nd year BSc Civil Engineering course) and Dynamics (1st year BSc Civil Engineering course).
- Organised practical sessions, question hours and occasionally study tours at the Waterlab, a laboratory belonging to Delft University of Technology.
- Improved and created assignments for the MSc course Ocean Waves in Python.

Student Mentor

August 2014 - July 2015

• Helped first-year BSc Civil Engineering students in making the transition from high school to university by organising weekly meetings and several other activities to make students feel at ease and to encourage social engagement with others.

NIOZ Royal Netherlands Institute for Sea Research

Crew Member

February 2018

- Participated as a student crew member on the RV Pelagia during leg 4 of the NICO expedition, in which the objective was to measure an ocean eddy in the Caribbean Sea. Made measurements of temperature and salinity, amongst others, with the use of a CTD. Acoustic and flow measurements were also made, which was incorporated in my data analysis.
- Publications are in progress. More information can be found on www.nico-expeditie.nl.

Witteveen+Bos

Intern

November 2017 – February 2018

- For my main project, I performed a data analysis of aeolian sediment transport at the Hondsbossche Dunes.
- Side projects: designed a floating caravan, further developed CoDeS (= Coastal Design Support tool, developed by Witteveen+Bos, Deltares and Royal HaskoningDHV), created an extreme wave analysis tool in Python, modelled the propagation of an oil spill in the ocean.

Canitiem

Core Team Member 'Studenten Hebben Dorst'

 $April\ 2015-October\ 2017$

• Published a new book called 'Studenten Hebben Dorst'. For more information, visit the website: www.studentenhebbendorst.nl.

Bijlesnetwerk

Private tutor

December 2013 - July 2014

• Tutored high school students at HAVO and VWO levels (higher general secondary and pre-university education respectively) in subjects such as chemistry, mathematics, history etc. This required good comprehension of the study material as well as excellent teaching ability.

bettermarks

Translator

January 2014 – June 2014

• Translated mathematics course material from English to Dutch at high school level. This required excellent proficiency of English and Dutch and also the ability to work in highly stressful situations. The goal was to create an online platform, which students can use to increase their knowledge and skills in mathematics.

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Data Science: Business and Governance, GPA 8.6/10.0 Tilburg School of Humanities and Digital Sciences, Tilburg University Specialised tracks: Deep Learning, Data Mining

January 2020 - July 2020

Finished one-year fulltime study programme in six months.

Master of Science, Hydraulic Engineering (Cum Laude), GPA 8.5/10.0 Civil Engineering and Geosciences, Delft University of Technology Thesis - Modelling the changes in waveform in combined wave-current flow Specialised tracks: Coastal/River/Dredging/Environmental Fluid Mechanics

September 2016 - May 2019

Bachelor of Science, Civil Engineering (Cum Laude), GPA 8.3/10.0 Civil Engineering and Geosciences, Delft University of Technology Thesis - MATLAB to Python: validation of moisture recycling in China

September 2013 - June 2016

Honours Programme, Civil Engineering Civil Engineering and Geosciences, Delft University of Technology Main courses: Philosophy of Science & Personal leadership Research project: The effects of measurements on backwater curves

September 2014 – June 2016

Gymnasium (highest level of secondary school) Utrechts Stedelijk Gymnasium NT/NG profiles (Nature, Technology and Health) Student council member (2011 – 2013)

September 2007 – July 2013

SKILLS AND INTERESTS

- Excellent in programming
 - very advanced: Python, MATLAB, Latex
 - proficient: Fortran, R, Google Docs, Microsoft Office (Excel)
- Modelling experiences with mathematical and numerical models such as SWASH, SWAN and Delft3D.
- Tends to be the leader in the group.
- Native proficiency in Dutch and Turkish, full professional proficiency in English.

• Interested in the latest developments in science and technology.

PUBLICATIONS

Research papers/reports

- "Investigating the effect of meditation on stress using a detection algorithm based on a deep neural network approach" (in press)
- "Modelling the changes in waveform in combined wave-current flow" (eprint)
- "A study on the environmental state of the Caribbean Sea in relation to the rapid intensification of tropical cyclone Matthew" (eprint)
- "The importance of moisture recycling in China", Report Series in Aerosol Science, 2nd PEEX Science Conference, 2016 (eprint)

Books

• "Studenten Hebben Dorst", https://studentenhebbendorst.nl/nl/

HONORS

- Bachelor's thesis nominated for Cees Boeter prize (best Bachelor's thesis in the field of Water Management)
- Certificate of Recognition, Shell Ideas360 Stage 2